Hello English learners, welcome back. We are here at EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
各位英语学习者，欢迎回来。这里是EnglishPod，我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're going to be bringing you a lesson about eggs.
今天我们要给大家带来一堂关于鸡蛋的课。
That's right. And who knew there was so much to talk about when we're talking eggs.
没错。谁能想到，聊鸡蛋还有这么多可说的呢。
Right. Well, we always have eggs for breakfast and there are many ways of preparing them,
是啊。我们早餐总是吃鸡蛋，而且有很多种做法，
so we're going to learn what the different ways are.
所以我们要学习这些不同的做法。
Yes, and we'll learn some of the language that goes along with eggs.
是的，我们还会学习一些和鸡蛋相关的语言表达。
Okay. So we have three words that we want to take a look at before we listen to our
好的。在听对话之前，我们先来看三个单词。
dialogue. So let's look at these in Vocabulary Preview.
我们来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
Our preview word for this lesson is picky.
这节课的预览词是“挑剔的”。
Picky.
挑剔的。
So picky is an interesting adjective.
“挑剔的”是一个有趣的形容词。
Okay. So if a person is picky, what does that mean?
好的。如果一个人很挑剔，那是什么意思？
They're very hard to please.
他们很难被取悦。
Okay. So if your boss is picky and you give him a report and maybe it has, I don't know,
好的。如果你的老板很挑剔，你给他一份报告，可能上面有，我不知道，
a couple of mistakes or something.
几个错误之类的。
Yeah, he'll say, do it again. Change this, this and this.
是啊，他会说，重做。改这个、这个和这个。
Okay.
好的。
So if you are picky, you want everything to be perfect.
所以如果你很挑剔，你希望一切都完美。
And if there's one small thing that's not, you won't be happy.
如果有一件小事不完美，你就不高兴。
Okay. So picky, interesting word. Now our next word, yolk.
好的。“挑剔的”是个有趣的词。下一个词，“蛋黄”。
Yolk.
蛋黄。
So this word is actually not in the dialogue.
这个词其实不在对话里。
It's not in the dialogue, but it's important that you know, right?
不在对话里，但你知道它很重要，对吧？
Okay. So if you have an egg, the yellow part is called the yolk.
好的。如果你有一个鸡蛋，黄色的部分叫蛋黄。
Okay. And what about the other part?
好的。那另一部分呢？
The white.
蛋白。
Or also called the egg white, right?
或者也叫蛋清，对吧？
Yes. Egg white.
是的。蛋清。
Okay. So pretty simple. Yolk and egg white.
好的。很简单。蛋黄和蛋清。
Let's listen to our dialogue. We are going to be listening to a couple who are having
我们来听对话。我们要听一对夫妻在……
breakfast.
早餐。
Wow. You're up early today. What's for breakfast?
哇，你今天起得真早。早餐吃什么？
Well, I felt like baking, so I made some muffins.
嗯，我想烤点东西，所以做了些松饼。
Smells good. I'll make some coffee. Do you want me to make you some eggs?
闻起来不错。我去煮点咖啡。要不要我给你做几个鸡蛋？
I'll take mine sunny side up.
我要单面煎的。
I don't know how you can eat your eggs like that. Ever since I was small, I've had eggs
我真不明白你怎么能那样吃鸡蛋。我从小就一直吃鸡蛋
and soldiers.
蘸面包条。
You know, my dad had scrambled eggs every morning for 20 years. It drove my mom crazy.
你知道吗，我爸爸连续20年每天早上都吃炒蛋，把我妈妈逼疯了。
You know what really drives me crazy? When I ask for soft boiled eggs and they overcook
你知道什么才真让我抓狂吗？我要溏心蛋，他们却煮过头
them so they come out hard boiled. How can you dip your toast into a hard boiled egg?
煮成了全熟蛋。你怎么能把吐司蘸进全熟蛋里？
You're so picky sometimes.
你有时候真挑剔。
Here you go, honey. Fried eggs.
给你，亲爱的。煎蛋。
Damn it. I said sunny side up. How many times do I have to tell you?
该死。我说了要单面煎。我得跟你说多少次？
So she is definitely very picky and has a very bad temper.
所以她确实非常挑剔，脾气也很差。
I know. I can't believe anyone would get so angry over their breakfast. But I guess it
我知道。真不敢相信有人会为早餐发这么大火。但我想
is the most important meal of the day.
这毕竟是一天中最重要的一餐。
Exactly. So we heard a couple of different ways of describing how you prepare eggs, so
没错。所以我们听到了几种描述鸡蛋做法的不同方式，
let's take a look at that in Language Takeaway.
接下来在“语言要点”中看看这些内容。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, so our first preparation method, my favorite, sunny side up.
好的，第一种做法，我的最爱，单面煎。
Okay, sunny side up.
好的，单面煎。
Sunny side up.
单面煎。
Now, this is interesting. Sunny, like the sun, right?
这很有意思。Sunny，像太阳一样，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So when you fry an egg, right, and the yolk looks like a little sun, right?
所以当你煎鸡蛋时，蛋黄看起来像个小太阳，对吧？
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
So why is it called sunny side up?
那为什么叫“单面煎”？
I think because of what you just said. It looks like the sun.
我想是因为你刚才说的。它看起来像太阳。
But you don't cook the yolk, right?
但你不把蛋黄煎熟，对吧？
Yeah, the yolk is still yellow. It's still a little bit liquid. It's a little bit soft.
对，蛋黄还是黄色的，还有点液态，有点软。
Okay, because the opposite would be a fried egg.
好的，因为相反的做法就是煎蛋。
Yes.
是的。
And that's our second word.
那是我们的第二个词。
Fried egg.
煎蛋。
So this, you put the egg in the pan and you cook it all the way through.
所以这个做法是把鸡蛋放进锅里，一直煎到全熟。
All the way through. So the yolk is not liquid anymore. It becomes hardened.
全熟，所以蛋黄不再是液态，变硬了。
Yes.
是的。
Right?
对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
A fried egg.
一个煎蛋。
Let's take a look at our next set of eggs.
我们来看看下一组鸡蛋。
All right.
好的。
A soft boiled egg.
一个溏心煮蛋。
Soft boiled.
溏心煮的。
Okay, so to boil, you put the egg?
好的，那么煮蛋就是把鸡蛋放进？
In water.
水里。
In boiling water.
在沸水里。
Yes, and make it cook.
是的，让它煮熟。
And make it cook. So how long would you usually put it in for to be soft boiled?
让它煮熟。那通常要煮多久才能做成溏心蛋？
Three minutes, four minutes.
三分钟，四分钟。
Three minutes, okay. So you only cook part of the egg, right?
三分钟，好的。所以只煮了鸡蛋的一部分，对吧？
The yolk, the yellow part, stays a little bit wet, a little bit liquid.
蛋黄，也就是黄色的部分，还保持一点湿润，有点液态。
Okay. So again, the opposite would be?
好的。那反过来呢？
A hard boiled egg.
全熟煮蛋。
Hard boiled egg.
Hard boiled.
全熟煮的。
So hard boiled is when you cook the entire egg again.
全熟煮蛋就是把整个鸡蛋都煮熟。
Yes, so then it's hard like a ball.
是的，所以它硬得像球一样。
The entire egg. So with this soft boiled and hard boiled eggs, this takes us to our next
整个鸡蛋。那么有了溏心煮蛋和全熟煮蛋，我们就进入下一种形式。
form, eggs and soldiers.
鸡蛋配士兵条。
Eggs and soldiers.
Now this is really interesting. I didn't really know about this before. It kind of sounds
这真的很有趣。我以前不太了解这个。听起来好像你在和一群军队士兵一起吃鸡蛋。
like you're having eggs with a group of soldiers from the army.
嗯，这是一种非常英式的吃鸡蛋方式。你把溏心煮蛋放在一个杯子里，然后有一片吐司。但吐司被切成长条。
Well, this is a very British way of eating eggs. So you have your soft boiled egg in
然后你拿起那些长条，蘸进蛋黄里。很好吃。
a cup and you have a piece of toast. But the toast is cut into long pieces.
不错。
And then you take those pieces and you dip them into the egg yolk. It's delicious.
是的。典型的英式吃鸡蛋方式。
It's good.
好的。所以鸡蛋配士兵条。有意思。这就带我们到了最后一种鸡蛋做法。
Yeah. Typical English way of eating eggs.
是的。炒蛋。
Okay. So eggs and soldiers. Interesting. And this takes us to our last form of egg preparation
炒蛋。
and probably the most popular.
Yes. Scrambled eggs.
炒蛋。
Scrambled eggs.
把鸡蛋放进平底锅，然后你就在锅里到处搅动它们。
炒蛋。
Take eggs, put them in a pan and then you just move them all over the place.
Mix them all up.
把它们全部混在一起。
So the yolk and the white are mixed together.
所以蛋黄和蛋白就混在一起了。
All right. So we've looked at a lot of egg preparation and now we can listen to our dialogue
好的。我们已经看了很多鸡蛋的烹饪方法，现在我们来听第二遍对话，
for the second time and then we'll come back and look at some phrases.
然后回来看看一些短语。
Wow. You're up early today. What's for breakfast?
哇。你今天起得真早。早餐吃什么？
Well, I felt like baking so I made some muffins.
嗯，我想烤点东西，所以做了些松饼。
Smells good. I'll make some coffee. Do you want me to make you some eggs?
闻起来真香。我来煮点咖啡。要不要我给你做点鸡蛋？
Sure. I'll take mine sunny side up.
好啊。我要单面煎的。
Ew. I don't know how you can eat your eggs like that. Ever since I was small, I've had
呃。我真不知道你怎么能那样吃鸡蛋。我从小就一直吃
eggs and soldiers.
鸡蛋配面包条。
You know, my dad had scrambled eggs every morning for 20 years. It drove my mom crazy.
你知道吗，我爸爸每天早上都吃炒鸡蛋，吃了20年。这让我妈妈快疯了。
You know what really drives me crazy? When I asked for soft boiled eggs and they overcook
你知道什么才真让我抓狂吗？当我要溏心蛋时，他们却煮过头，
them so they come out hard boiled. How can you dip your toast into a hard boiled egg?
结果煮成了全熟蛋。你怎么能把吐司蘸进全熟蛋里？
You're so picky sometimes.
你有时候真挑剔。
Here you go, honey. Fried eggs.
给你，亲爱的。煎蛋。
Damn it. I said sunny side up. How many times do I have to tell you?
该死。我说了要单面煎的。我要跟你说多少次？
Interesting that the man in this dialogue is the one doing the baking.
有意思，这段对话里的男人是那个在烤东西的人。
Yeah. Well, that's modern days. I don't know. Men are learning how to cook and yeah.
是啊。嗯，这就是现代。我不知道。男人也在学做饭，是啊。
House husband.
家庭主夫。
House husband. Yeah. More popular these days.
家庭主夫。是啊。现在更流行了。
All right. Well, since this house husband felt like baking, I think we should look at
好的。既然这位家庭主夫想烤东西，我觉得我们应该看看
this and one other phrase in Fluency Builder.
这个和流畅表达里的另一个短语。
Okay. So great phrase. He said, I felt like baking.
好的。很棒的短语。他说，我想烤东西。
I felt like baking.
我想烤东西。
I felt like baking. So let's take a look at this. He feels like or he felt like in the
我想烤东西。我们来看看这个。他感觉想，或者过去时他感觉想。
past. What does that mean when you feel like?
当你感觉想做什么时，是什么意思？
You want to do it. You have the desire to do it.
你想做它。你有做它的欲望。
Okay. And then to bake. And now this verb is in the gerund form.
好的。然后是烤。现在这个动词是动名词形式。
That's right. The ing form.
没错。就是ing形式。
And that's the rule, right? I feel like playing soccer.
这就是规则，对吧？我想踢足球。
Right. I feel like eating lunch.
对。我想吃午饭。
I felt like going to the movies. That's the way you would say this. You have the desire.
我想去看电影。这就是你要说的方式。你有欲望。
You feel like doing something.
你想做某事。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay. Very good. And now let's take a look at this second phrase. Drives me crazy.
好的。非常好。现在我们来看看第二个短语。让我抓狂。
Drives me crazy.
让我抓狂。
All right. This is a very, very descriptive phrase. And I think if we listen to some examples,
好的。这是一个非常非常生动的短语。我想如果我们听一些例子，
it will help us understand the meaning.
会帮助我们理解它的意思。
Example one. This music is driving me crazy. Turn it down.
例一。这音乐快把我逼疯了。关小点声。
Example two. Don't leave garbage in my car. It drives me crazy.
例子二。别把垃圾留在我车里。这让我抓狂。
Example three. Your mom is driving me crazy. She keeps calling me.
例子三。你妈快把我逼疯了。她老是给我打电话。
All right. So if something drives you crazy.
好的。所以如果某件事让你抓狂。
It makes you feel very angry or annoyed.
它让你感到非常生气或恼火。
Irritated.
恼怒。
Yeah. Frustrated.
是的。很沮丧。
Okay. But it can also be positive, right? Like that girl drives me crazy.
好的。但也可以表示正面意思，对吧？比如“那个女孩让我着迷”。
As in you really, really, really like her.
就像是你真的、真的、非常喜欢她。
Yeah.
是的。
I don't know. It sounds a little bit inappropriate to me.
我不知道。对我来说，这听起来有点不太合适。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是的。
I think it's okay. It drives me crazy. Like she's got me thinking and she's got me in
我觉得还行。这快把我逼疯了。她让我胡思乱想，还把我卷进去了。
the clouds or something like that.
云啊什么的。
All right. Well, maybe there's something about you that I don't need to know. So I'll just
好吧。也许你有些事我不需要知道。那我就算了。
let you keep that thought to yourself.
你最好还是把那个想法憋在心里吧。
All right. Well, I'm just saying we could use it in a positive form as well.
好吧。我只是说我们也可以用肯定形式来表达。
Okay. You're just saying.
好的，你只是说说而已。
I'm just saying. All right. So drives me crazy. Really great phrase. And you can use it in
我只是说说而已。好吧。这让我抓狂。非常棒的短语。你可以在以下情况使用它：
all of these different situations like we heard. So let's listen to our dialogue for
所有这些不同的情况，就像我们听到的那样。那么，让我们来听一下我们的对话吧。
the last time and then we'll come back and talk a little bit more.
最后一次，然后我们回来再聊一会儿。
Wow. You're up early today. What's for breakfast?
哇，你今天起得真早。早餐吃什么？
Well, I felt like baking so I made some muffins.
嗯，我突然想烤点东西，就做了些松饼。
Smells good. I'll make some coffee. Do you want me to make you some eggs?
闻起来不错。我来煮点咖啡。要不要我给你煎几个蛋？
Sure. I'll take mine sunny side up.
好的，我的蛋要单面煎。
I don't know how you can eat your eggs like that. Ever since I was small, I've had eggs
我不知道你怎么能那样吃鸡蛋。从小时候起，我就一直吃鸡蛋。
and soldiers.
以及士兵们。
You know, my dad had scrambled eggs every morning for 20 years. It drove my mom crazy.
你知道吗，我爸爸每天早上都吃炒鸡蛋，吃了整整20年。这让我妈妈快疯了。
You know what really drives me crazy? When I ask for soft boiled eggs and they overcook
你知道什么最让我抓狂吗？就是我要溏心蛋，结果他们煮过头了。
them so they come out hard boiled. How can you dip your toast into a hard boiled egg?
这样煮出来的蛋就是全熟的。那你怎么能把吐司蘸进全熟蛋里呢？
You're so picky sometimes. Here you go, honey. Fried eggs.
你有时候真挑剔。来，亲爱的，煎蛋好了。
Damn it. I said sunny side up. How many times do I have to tell you?
该死。我说的是单面煎蛋。我要跟你说多少次？
Well, I think there are some people who really, really love eating eggs for breakfast and
嗯，我觉得有些人真的特别特别喜欢早餐吃鸡蛋。
some people who just can't stand it.
有些人就是受不了。
Yeah. I don't know who though. I mean, who doesn't like eggs in the morning?
是啊。不过我不知道是谁。我是说，谁早上会不喜欢吃鸡蛋呢？
I know. I'm a big fan.
我知道。我是你的超级粉丝。
Right? Eggs, bacon, toast. Good stuff.
对吧？鸡蛋、培根、吐司。好东西。
Traditional American type breakfast.
传统美式早餐。
Now you were telling me that you have some traditions when you eat eggs.
你刚才跟我说，你们吃鸡蛋的时候有一些传统习惯。
I know. I think, I'm not sure if this is just in my family, but I think actually it might
我知道。我觉得，我不确定这是不是只有我家这样，但我想可能其他人也有类似的情况。
be common with other people as well. When you eat a soft boiled or hard boiled egg,
当你吃溏心蛋或全熟蛋的时候，
you have to eat all of the egg outside of the shell and then you have to break the bottom
你必须把蛋壳外面的蛋全部吃完，然后吃完后还要把蛋壳底部敲碎。
of the shell after you finished.
Why?
为什么？
So that the fairies who live in your egg cup can come out.
这样住在你蛋杯里的仙女才能出来。
So it's kind of like a superstition.
所以这有点像一种迷信。
Yeah, I guess it is.
是啊，我想是的。
Interesting.
有意思。
Yeah. So I don't know. You guys, do you have any egg traditions or any other crazy food
是啊。所以我不知道。你们呢，有没有什么关于鸡蛋的传统或者其他疯狂的食物故事？
stories like that?
像那样的？
Well, for example, I was telling you that when I prepare scrambled eggs, sometimes I
嗯，比如，我跟你说过，当我做炒蛋的时候，有时候
like to take some rice, some rice that has already been cooked, put it in the pan and
我喜欢拿一些米饭，一些已经煮好的米饭，放进锅里，
then take some eggs, two eggs, put it on top of the rice and scramble the rice with the
然后拿两个鸡蛋，放在米饭上面，把米饭和鸡蛋一起炒。
eggs.
Okay. For breakfast?
好的。当早餐吃？
Yeah, it could be for breakfast.
是啊，可以当早餐。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah. A little bit. Not like a huge plate of rice or maybe at night you don't have anything
是啊，一点点。不是一大盘米饭，或者可能晚上没什么东西吃的时候。
to eat.
Okay.
好的。
Scrambled eggs with rice. It's a poor man's food.
炒蛋配米饭。这是穷人的食物。
All right. Well, it's also a quick man's food.
好吧，这也是快手餐。
Yeah, exactly. So let us know if you guys have any egg preparations or any special egg
是啊，没错。所以请告诉我们，你们有没有什么鸡蛋的做法，或者特别的鸡蛋食谱或传统？
recipes or traditions that you practice.
Visit our website at EnglishPod.com where you can leave all of your comments and questions.
访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，你可以在那里留下所有评论和问题。
Exactly. And as always, we are there to answer them and solve any problems.
没错。和往常一样，我们会在那里回答它们并解决任何问题。
Well, we're out of time for today, but until next time, bye.
好吧，我们今天时间到了，但下次再见，拜拜。